Eniola Oseni

oseni eniola@yahoo.com

Full Stack Developer

LinkedIn

+2349050174801

Solution-driven Full Stack Developer with 4+ years using a combination of different technology frameworks ranging from Angular, Nodejs, React, and Java springBoot to build user-friendly and mobile responsive software and applications. Proven experience with Software systems design, database development, infrastructure deployment and administration, coordinating and pushing new releases to production infrastructure using Amazon Web Services (AWS). Automates and orchestrates application deployment process by building docker images to containerise applications for accessible deployment of on-premises and Cloud infrastructures.

CORE TOOLS

- React
- Angular
- HTML5
- NodeJS
- Java Spring Boot

- CSS/ SCSS
- JIRA
- ExpressJS
- TypeScript
- GIT|GITHUB

- Docker
- REST API
- Azure Devops
- Gitlab
- NEWGEN IBPS

CORE SKILLS

- Teamwork & Collaboration
- Stakeholder Management
- Adaptability & Accountability
- Software Development Life Cycle
- Website Application Development
- Programming
- Analytical Skills
- Code Conversion
- Software Designs
- Database Technology
- Problem-Solving
- Business Analysis
- Organisation skills
- Automated Testing
- Project Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Engineer

2022 - Present

Wakanow

- Design and build of a user firiendly and responsive travel and lifestyle platform Onburd.com, which has generated large volume of transactions for the business.
- Integration with various payment systems and 3rd party platforms
- Collaborate with technical team members to analyse new and existing code, do unit testing, and conduct root cause analysis of issues to identify ideas to enhance system performance.

Backend Engineer (Contract)

2022 - Present

Zenith Bank

- Maintenance and update of the corporate banking application, which has helped improved how corporate carry out their day to day transactions and also generated high volume of transactions and liquidity for the bank
- Implementation of new features and updates

- Collaboration with business and technical team to review new business requirements, review code, support
 application testing and deployment
- Integration and consuming different Rest endpoint as well as connecting with 3rd party endpoints

Senior Software Engineer 2022 – 2022

Union Systems

- Design and develop software using a variety of languages and technologies to satisfy specified acceptance criteria and stories, ensuring the agile team adhered to development standards.
- Successfully develop Back-end API for international trade systems and 3rd party banking integrations
- Collaborate with technical team members to analyse new and existing code, do unit testing, and conduct root cause analysis of issues to identify ideas to enhance system performance.
- Translate business and functional requirements into technical solutions and user interface designs, helping
 with post-launch bug fixes for software components that are not performing as planned.
- Develop a user-friendly interface with an analytics dashboard for systems used in international trade.
- Ensure unit and integration testing of code and provide support to testing cycles ensuring that defects are resolved
- Integrate different back-end tools through efficient APIs and back-end analytical processes and automate the matching platform.
- Develop code in React, NextJS, GraphQL and other frameworks whilst performing L2 application support and optimisation.

Software Developer 2019 – 2022

Verraki Africa

- Utilised Angular, Typescript, HTML, and SCSS to implement the front-end design across the POS, ADMIN, and MY MEDICINE modules for the Advantage Health Africa web application.
- Led the automation and implementation of the TOD (Temporary Overdraft) process at First Bank Plc. successfully utilising NEWGEN IBPS, Java, and JavaScript, which slashed the redundant procedure by 65% and improved processing times for clients and staff by 45%.
- Successfully delivered the agile software development cycle to create microservices for a time and cost
 management system that uses the REST API, Angular for front-end development, and STRAPI for content
 management.
- Oversaw all client projects with full-stack development and reduced lead time by 15% by optimising consultation duration.
- Executed containerising of the Process Maker and GAPS applications at GTBank Plc., which facilitated Agile development and resulted in a 17% increase in customer satisfaction, efficiency of the apps, and eased the management system
- Designed architecture for microservices, containerisation and automation of application deployment using Docker and Kubernetes.
- Achieved a 99% uptime of web apps by deploying, sustaining, and maintaining them on the AWS cloud.

IT Support Engineer 2018 – 2019

Straighttalk Technologies

- Installed security software and hardware, and trained staff on IT security and recommended further security measures to be adopted.
- Increased UX ratings by 20% by improving the website design and user interface
- Managed the corporate website and fixed hardware, system, and phone issues, enhancing departmental productivity by 25%.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Implemented the front-end design for the Advantage Health Africa web application across POS, ADMIN & MY MEDICINE modules using Angular, Typescript, HTML & SCSS.
- Led the automation and implementation of the TOD (Temporary Overdraft) process at First Bank Plc., successfully utilising NEWGEN IBPS, Java, and JavaScript, which slashed the redundant procedure by 65% and improved processing times for clients and staff by 45%.
- Achieved 99% uptime when deploying and maintaining web apps on the AWS Cloud.
 Successfully delivered the API integrations for the Commercial Paper process using Newgen IBP.
- Developed a back-end API for third-party banking connections and Kachasi's international trade systems and provided specialist advice to the business support unit and end users, enhancing customer retention by 35%.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science
 2018
 Federal University of Agriculture Abeokuta

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (Verification no: L0TS1LXJHM111YCY)
 2021
- Newgen Technical Certification Level 1 & 2 2021
- SIIT Diploma Certificate of Achievement (Data Communication) 2019
- Oracle Java Boot Camp 2018